<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode
	icon="../icons/compass.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Start WebDriver</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Starts a Selenium subworkflow by creating a new WebDriver.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>

        <p>This node starts a <a href="http://www.seleniumhq.org">Selenium</a> subworkflow by opening a WebDriver.
        A WebDriver serves as an interface to a web browser, and allows to open web pages, control the browser, and
        extract data from it. The actual WebDriver to use must be configured using an upstream <i>WebDriver Factory</i>
        node.</p>

        <p>To automatically close the browser after your Selenium workflow is finished, you can terminate your workflow
        with a <!-- node-ref="QuitWebDriver" --><i>Quit WebDriver</i><!-- /node-ref --> node.</p>

        <p><b>Important note:</b> Because of the way Selenium works, KNIME workflows using the Selenium nodes behave
        differently than you might be used from other nodes. As a Selenium workflow relies on a running browser instance,
        it is for example not possible to re-run a saved KNIME workflow from in between after it has been loaded from disk.
        In such cases, you need to re-run the workflow starting from the initial <i>Start WebDriver</i> node, as the
        downstream Selenium node require a WebDriver instance for operation.</p>

        </intro>
        <tab name="Options">
	        <option name="URL">The URL to load (optional)</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Timeouts">
        	<option name="Page load timeout">The timeout for a page load to finish in milliseconds.</option>
        	<option name="Script timeout">The timeout for asynchronous scripts in milliseconds.</option>
        	<option name="Implicit wait">The amount of time to wait in case an element is searched in the DOM and
        	it is not immediately available.</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
    	<inPort index="0" name="WebDriver Factory">A configured factory which is used for creating the WebDrivers</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="WebDriver">A table with one row and column providing the WebDriver</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
